ANABELLA GUIMAREY - Technical Project Manager

email: anabellag7[at]gmail[dot]com - website: www.anabellag7.com - location: Buenos Aires, Argentina

4+ years of experience in IT. Extreme ownership, self-starter, very technical. Special skills and experience on startups and leading cross-functional remote teams.

Areas of Knowledge

- Experience managing complex projects on fast-paced startups.
- Hyper-organized and capable of juggling all of the data associated with projects and task-tracking.
- Skilled at **communicating** across a diverse set of engineers and their stakeholders (other engineers, product managers, customer-facing individuals, and directors).
- Interested in **learning** everything about the product.

Professional Experience

AutoCloud - 1 mo

Senior Technical Project Manager (August 2021 - Present)

ASAPP - 2 yrs 2 mos

Senior Technical Project Manager (April 2020 – August 2021)

Management of projects for two backend teams and one heavy-frontend. Facilitator of scrum and kanban ceremonies. Worked on exposing a bulletproof tool to clients. Managed two high-impact IT projects.

Technical Project Manager (July 2019 - April 2020)

The first TPM hired at the Argentina office. Managed more than 12 concurrent projects for 3 remote product engineering teams. Performed the scrum master role. Helped architect the company's planning workflow.

Auravant - 2 yrs 1 mo

Product and Engagement Manager (December 2017 - May 2019)

Set the product vision and build the company's roadmap. Hands-on collaboration with the engineering team to ensure iteration and production of actionable insights. Creator of every Product Requirements Document.

Front-end Developer (May 2017 - December 2017)

The first employee to join the startup. I worked alongside the CTO to create the UI for the best selling product, using Javascript, HTML, CSS and Bootstrap, from design to development. Maintenance of the company's website using WordPress and PHP.

YPF - 1 yr

Geology intern (June 2016 - May 2017)

Internship at an Oil & Gas company. Assisted with geologic calculations using computer-based technical tools. Data input and analysis, including preparing maps, tables, and figures with GIS.

Education

Master of Information Technology - Universidad de Palermo (2020 - 2022)

Bachelor of Science in Geology - Universidad de Buenos Aires (2011 - 2018)

Languages

English (fluent), Spanish (native).